and today on the channel we are going to
use this salted
caramel salted butter caramel actually
it's called from Costco to make a salted
caramel gelato in the Ninja
creamy so I picked this up from Costco
oh 6 months ago maybe even more than
that and it's just salted butter caramel
from France 660 mil and it consists of
per 60 G per 60 mlit actually 6 G of fat
56 G of carbs of which 49 g of sugar and
2 G Protein that's pretty much it and
it's got sugar which is cane sugar
glucose syrup and condensed milk cream
which has got caragan in it uh butter
salt and then the caramel mix so which
is sugar and water and it's thickened
with
AAR um with all that stuff in it we can
make gelat pretty easily with just three
other ingredients milk cream and a
little bit of skim mil powder to bring
the numbers back up so let's make this
in ninja creamy the OG
one so there's our
tubs and we're going to when it's
finished we're going to add a little bit
of this which is um valona Dolce 35%
blonde it's like caramelized white
chocolate milk chocolate hybrid um so
yeah nice and easy let's just weigh
everything out as there's stabilizer
already in here AAR it's pretty decent
as it is but we've got stabilizer we got
AAR in here we've got caragan in here as
well our cream here has caragan in it
we're not going to add any more
stabilizer to it so we're going to do
this nice and simply we're going to get
a bowl and in there we're going to get
our milk and cream we need 600 G of milk
into that we're going to add 250 g of
cream whipping cream if if your cream is
36 33 34% don't worry about it if you
use double cream and UK it will be
slightly higher fat content shouldn't be
an issue so 250 g we're going to need
put these away 30 G of skim milk
powder whisk that
together and finally our salted caramel
or salted butter caramel we only 225
G man that was tight there we
go Tes nice now we are simply going to
pop this in the microwave probably for
about a minute on high it's fine just
literally warm enough to get that
caramel moving around inside we can put
it back in if we need to which I think
we do let's try again yeah that's
better that caramel wasn't wasn't uh
mixing in with the dairy so a little bit
more heat and there we go we've now got
caramel colored
liquid which is exactly what we
want and that's pretty much it now let's
pour it in our
tubs and in the freezer they go so once
it's ready I mean this has been in
overnight we're going to take it out of
the freezer pop the lid off and pop it
in our machine this is gelato you can
spin on gelato setting if you like or
ice cream doesn't make any difference
cuz the speed is exactly the same even
what it does is exactly the same so it's
just the same whilst that's processing
and stening my next on neighbor we're
going to prepare some chocolate this is
that caramel flavored chocolate from
Verona but you can use a caram milk a
caramac or anything like that that is
like a caramel flavored chocolate and in
the midst we're going to take a spoon
make a nice hole in the middle put some
of that chocolate in there take a taste
out of the ice cream make sure it's good
have a wand around in the kitchen and
you know try and find your other shoe
that's missing then when it's ready
we're going to take it out and Dish some
up
there we go Costco's salted caramel
salted butter caramel there loads on
there gelato easy to use use very few
ingredients let's see how this turned
out
delicious Costco straight off the shelf
no problems that is just a
perfect marriage spoon fillets on top
sprinkle some of this on and you've got
something that is
beautiful
so nice easy salted caramel gelato using
Costco salted butter caramel using this
straight from
Costco if you don't have this get
something like a caramac that would work
really well with this as well anyway
thanks so much for watching don't forget
to like And subscribe and I will see you
next week